

# **Gustavo Rayos**













575-520-5199

gustavorayos @outlook.com San Francisco Bay Area

gustavorayos.com

@gustavorayos

@qustavorayos

#### Summary

Dedicated Computer Systems Engineer since 2015. Currently holds an active DoD Secret Security <u>Clearance</u> and is <u>CompTIA Security+ Certified</u>. Experienced in Information Systems Engineering, Systems Administration, Systems Automation and Deployment, and Cyber Security. Performs system configuration, deployment automation, workstation patching, vulnerability management, and system analysis. Received Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science from New Mexico State University in 2015.

#### Skills

#### LANGUAGES

- Bash
- Python
- PowerShell
- DOS/Windows
- JavaScript
- CSS
- HTML

#### **TECHNOLOGIES**

- Linux (RHEL)
- SCAP
- STIGViewer
- VMWare
- Hyper-V
- Ansible
- NetApp

- Active Directory
- Group Policy
- WDS & MDT
- SCCM
- DNS & DHCP
- Tenable
- MacOS

#### Experience

### CARETAKER / OFFICE MANAGER

#### Rayos Construction | Las Cruces, NM | March 2023 - March 2024

- Coordinated with customers setting up schedules for home repairs and remodels.
- Acted as point of contact for customer questions or concerns.
- Assisted with construction purchases and needs in the field.
- Supplied other employees with tools needed to complete tasks in the field.

### SENIOR INFORMATION SYSTEMS SECURITY ENGINEER (DOD SECRET SECURITY CLEARANCE) Lockheed Martin Space | Sunnyvale, CA | November 2020 - March 2023

- Designed and developed software/scripts to automate Linux and Windows deployments.
- Performed Cyber-security tasks such as vulnerability scanning and applying system SCANs, STIGs, Controls, and Policies.
- Deployed and administered NetApp storage device.
- Migrated data from end-of-life (EOL) NetApp storage device to new NetApp using OnTap.
- Restored deleted files for users using NetApp snapmirror.
- Performed remediation, developed POAMs, and supported 3<sup>rd</sup> party and internal security audits.
- Worked closely with networking team to troubleshoot network (Infoblox) issues between client and server.
- Configured DNS and DHCP services on Linux (RHEL) and Windows servers and workstations.
- Developed Kickstart script/process automate Linux workstation and server deployments.
- Designed and developed scripts to harden/configure systems to meet compliance standards of Defense Information Systems Agency (DISA).
- Deployed Tang services to automate the access of LUKs encrypted drives on the network.
- Designed virtualized test environment to test software, systems, and other deployments before production.

- Deployed and administered Ansible Configuration Management server on multiple networks.
- Deployed authentication NIS server on information systems.
- Configured Real Time Systems (RedHawk) for THAAD Missile System.
- Automated log collection, log scanning, SCAP scanning and STIG configuration.
- Patched RHEL 6 and 7 systems to STIG configuration.
- Analyzed and assessed server performance, storage capacity and planning for future needs.
- Deployed NetApp storage device.
- Performed server/workstation patching per guidelines working closely with Cyber Security.
- Physically installed server and associated hardware in data center and server room.
- Successfully installed/configured software; Gitlab, Docker, Doors, Matlab, etc.
- Created/edited Standard Operating Instructions (SOI) documentation.
- DoD Secret Security Clearance.

#### SYSTEMS ENGINEER (DOD SECRET SECURITY CLEARANCE)

### Raytheon Missile Systems | Tucson, AZ | March 2019 - October 2020

- Developed software packages to automate standard OS configuration on test equipment.
- Deployed a Windows Deployment Server (WDS) and Microsoft Deployment Toolkit (MDT) server and was responsible for task sequence configuration and client system deployment.
- Configured Windows and RHEL operating system to STIG standards.
- Worked closely with Cyber Security configuring hardware and software.
- Attended Sigma Six discussions providing useful feedback as a member of a project team.
- Participated in system design, security solutions, system imaging, data recovery, hardware diagnostics, and unique problem solutions in multiple heterogeneous network environments.
- Assisted with managing user accounts, network access, generation and maintenance of web-page content, infrastructure, database support, and system backups.
- DoD Secret Security Clearance.

#### SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATOR (DOE Q SECURITY CLEARANCE)

#### CNS Pantex | Amarillo, TX | December 2015 - March 2019

- Attended weekly Vulnerability Assessment Management meetings with Cyber Security and discussing vulnerabilities and remediation plans on systems.
- Calculated Site Performance Review (SPR) monthly metrics, and reviewed system compliance on the Pantex network. Average monthly system compliance on the Pantex network was 99% compliant.
- Reviewed and approved non-standard security exceptions for individual users and systems.
- Developed security protocols and procedures using various tools including PowerShell scripts, SCCM, Group Policy, Active Directory, Tenable, Splunk, Citrix, and more.
- Created and configured standalone system media for government issued laptops which included Cisco AnyConnect VPN software.
- Acted as a direct contact for various software deployments.
- Acted as a direct contact for any VPN related issues.
- DoE Q Top Secret Security Clearance

#### Education

#### BACHELORS DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

#### New Mexico State University | Las Cruces, NM | August 2010 - December 2015

Followed my passion for computers and programming and excelled in Java and C programming courses, network security and architecture, and completed research on HPC systems and software. Minored in Software Development and Algorithms Theory. Graduated with a 3.5 GPA.

# **Gustavo Rayos**

#### Cover Letter

My background is in system engineering with an emphasis on cyber security, vulnerability management, system and network scanning, and systems automation and deployment. I have 8 years' experience working closely with system administration, engineering, and cyber security teams preparing information systems to undergo various auditing processes and procedures.

My duties at Lockheed Martin, Raytheon, and CNS Pantex were to act as the primary System Engineer and Administrator for various classified information systems that undergo auditing to meet requirements of the Department of Defense and Department of Energy. For this, I use various automation and scanning tools to find and remediate vulnerabilities. My day to day duties require the technical skills needed to design, develop, and deploy the things necessary to automate tasks that are a part of the vulnerability management process.

In addition to my responsibilities preparing for audits, my duties are also to act as a system administrator for engineers working on the program. This requires vast knowledge of many technologies including virtualization (VMware, Hyper-V, Virtualbox), software deployments (Ansible, SCCM), active directory management (AD, Group Policy Management), and usual tasks of a system administrator.

I wish to continue learning and refining my skills in this field and am motivated to be a respected and knowledgeable engineer for a respectable and great company.

Thanks,

Gustavo